i know what people like to do you like
to go to the gym you like to have
everything there for you you don't want
to bring a bunch of stuff you know most
people aren't going to pack 15 different
bands in their gym bag and then carry
around with them while they work out and
gym owners aren't going to want to
supply bands because not only do they
disappear you know people steal them but
they're also a liability risk because
the bands can break so even though this
isn't the most practical style of
training i'm going to tell you why i
believe that bar plus band training or
just adding bands to straight resistance
is a superior form of training and might
be the optimal way to train especially
for the types of people who get really
sore or are injury prone wouldn't it be
pretty cool if 10 years from now you
know research emerges we found out that
i was right nevertheless i hope you give
it a try and form your own opinion but
yes if you had to pick one form of
resistance you know like body weight
dumbbell
bar bar plus band pure band you know
kettlebell machine i do believe bar plus
band could very well be the most
superior form of training across the
board
[Music]
in this video i'm gonna first tell you
why i think adding bands to the bar
might very well be the most superior
form of training for muscle hypertrophy
and even better than pure barbell
training i'm going to teach you the
biomechanics of the different forms of
resistance i'm going to touch upon the
research pertaining to band training but
i'm also going to tell you why we can't
have a study or it would be very hard to
have a study that really provides solid
evidence as to which is superior bar
plus band or barbell and then i'm going
to end things off with teaching you all
the ways that we use bands at glute lab
in our own training all right so let me
paint three different scenarios for you
you know one scenario is pure barbell
training that's where you take a bar off
the rack you know lower it to your chest
press it up or you put a bar on your
back you know squat squat down squat
back up rack it that's barbell
resistance and it's a straight
even resistance throughout the whole
range of motion right now another form
would be pure band training where you
just have bands like for example if you
wrap the bands underneath a bench i i
like to use the the bands with handles
or if you do standing band presses you
know hook the band to the rack the bands
with handles walk far out and then press
them that's pure band training right
it's hard to do with lower body exercise
but we do do it with some of them but
that's pure band training and that
starts out with like very little
resistance like little to no resistance
and then as you stretch it increases
more and more such that at the lockout
you get the most resistance or maximum
resistance at the very top when you've
locked the weight out and finally
there's a combination of those two you
know bar plus band resistance where you
kind of get the best of both worlds so
let's say i'm doing bar plus band bench
press all right say i have 225 around
the bar but then i have bands wrapped
around which add another 100 pounds of
tension at the bottom i will have 225 at
the top i will have 325 and then
logically in the middle it would be
around 275 pounds so when you
incorporate bands this is known as
variable resistance because it's
variable the resistance changes
throughout the range of motion in
comparison with barbell where you have
the same resistance throughout the
entire range of motion and in the
literature adding bands is appropriately
termed variable resistance but in
strength training circles you know
amongst strength coaches power lifters
when you read blogs you'll often read
accommodating resistance now let me tell
you why that's not a good term the
reason why people call accommodating
resistance is because many popular lifts
have what's known as ascending strength
curves which means your strength
increases throughout the range of motion
chances are you can quarter squat a lot
more than you can deep squat most people
can rack pull more than they can
deadlift off the floor so you have five
boards on your chest you can do a lot
more weight with a five board press than
you could when touching your chest so
because we're stronger throughout the
range of motion because you gain a
mechanical advantage meaning that your
leverage tends to improve throughout the
range of motion when you add bands or
chains what you're doing is essentially
accommodating the strength curve you're
trying to make up for that mechanical
advantage by adding bands or chains so
that it's hard throughout the entire
range of motion you will notice when you
use barbells you tend to have a sticking
region now the sticking region is the
region where bar velocity slows down
throughout the movement okay you might
notice in the squat you know you have a
lot of power out of the hole those first
few inches you come up fast then you
tend to slow down and most people stall
you know up above parallel but if you
make it out of that region it's easy now
there are various regions for the
sticking region which are beyond the
scope of this video but if bands were
perfect then you wouldn't have a
sticking region you know it would be
super hard throughout the whole range of
motion and every extra inch would be
just as hard as the previous inch but
because of the nature of the sticking
region you can't perfectly match the
strength curve you see the same things
with machines they use what's known as
cams which change the resistance
leverage throughout the range of motion
to try to match your own strength curve
you use a pec deck you're stronger out
here than you are in here but the cam
never quite feels right because it's
really hard to match the human strength
curve and that curve varies according to
the individual we're all different now
that said
there are exercises where you're not
stronger throughout the range of motion
you know think of chin-ups chin-ups are
usually hardest at the lockout think of
hip thrust they're usually hardest at
the lockout too seated rows you can't
partial seated row a lot more than you
can full range seated row and even in
some lifts like deadlifts you'll see
some people who can you know block a
rack pull a ton other people are
actually weaker with their block pull
compared to their regular deadlift i'm
one of those weird individuals where i
could do a three inch deficit deadlift i
could do a conventional deadlift from
the floor and a three inch block pull
and my strength doesn't change that much
so yeah your strength curve depends on
you it's very individual specific when
you use bands or chains you're not
perfectly accommodating the strength
curve so it shouldn't be really known as
accommodating resistance it should be
appropriately termed variable resistance
okay got it good now to the most
important part of this video okay the
rationale picture someone doing a
barbell back squat okay they have say
500 pounds on their back okay they go
down they go down they go down and now
they're real deep and they reverse it as
they reverse out of the hole all the
muscles are stretched you know quads are
being stretched glutes are being
stretched adductors are being stretched
and think of what the muscle is trying
to do the muscle is contracting which
means it's trying to pull together but
it's trying to pull together as it's
being lengthened the eccentric phase is
characterized by a muscle contracting
trying to shorten as it's being forcibly
lengthened so that process creates
muscle damage and the farther you
stretch the more muscle damage you
create we used to think this was because
of this popping sarcomere hypothesis
where you're basically tearing
sarcomeres but now we kind of believe
it's due to an influx of calcium kind of
like flooding the stretch-activated ion
channels but regardless of the
physiological mechanism you get more
damage during eccentric contractions and
contractions that long muscle length the
greater the stretch the more damage you
get and then the greater the load in the
stretch the more damage you get picture
a band hip thrust okay at the bottom not
a lot of tension as you rise up you rise
up you get to the full lockout
then it's really really hard it's really
pushing you down and you're squeezing
your glutes like crazy but all the
tension is in that shortened position
that end range contraction so think
about the movements that make you the
most sore okay
for me
flies you know because i take dumbbells
and i go deep you know i heard arnold
talking about how his he would do flies
and the dumbbells would almost touch the
floor
[Music]
so when i do flies i am stretching like
crazy they get my pecs so sore when i do
stiff leg deadlifts my hamstrings always
get sore dumbbell walking lunges get my
glutes thesaurus you'll think about you
take a big step and you go down deep and
you get this big stretch on your glute
so it's logical to think wow these are
the best exercise for muscle growth
because they do stretch you the most
their hardest in the stretch and the
outdated viewpoint of muscle growth was
well you got to tear a muscle down and
then it grows back stronger you know
think of like a callus that you form you
know you keep wearing it down and then
it keeps growing back stronger but
interestingly that's not how muscle
hypertrophy works it's not the greater
the muscle damage the more muscle you
grow out of the three proposed
mechanisms of muscle growth mechanical
tension metabolic stress and muscle
damage it's sort of a consensus that
muscle damage is the least important and
there's also a lot of evidence showing
that it can be detrimental to
hypertrophy okay you can do too much
volume or too many eccentric
contractions or too much load in the
stretch and it can make you too damaged
you know too sore such that you can't
have a productive training session
several days later you know think of
that time where you went crazy you went
berserk in the gym and you just did way
too much and you couldn't walk properly
for like five days your whole training
week was shot you didn't have a good
lower body training session three four
days later you had to wait till the
following week to be recovered so i'm
not proposing that pure band training is
superior to barbell training i think you
do need tension in the stretch so pure
band training there's nothing in the
stretch and it's everything in the
squeeze but a lot of barbell exercise
it's like too much tension in the
stretch and not enough tension in the
squeeze so by taking a loaded barbell
and then adding band resistance you get
the best of both worlds you get a little
bit less tension in the stretch a little
bit more tension in the squeeze and by
doing so you eliminate a lot of the
muscle damage and because you don't have
a lot of muscle damage you aren't going
to have a lot of muscle soreness you're
going to be able to train the lifts and
the muscles more frequently in the
research it doesn't appear that training
frequency is that important we know that
two times a week is definitely better
than one time a week but above that if
volume is matched there's not a lot of
support for three and four and five
times a week but i believe that this
would be different if we did research on
barbell versus barbell plus band
training so think about it how many
really hard sets of barbell squats can
you do in a week let's say you do six
hard sets like really hard like you know
one to two reps shy of failure most
people couldn't do that three times a
week most people could only do that
twice a week so you're getting 12 hard
sets in per week think about hip thrusts
how many hard sets of hip dress can you
do it still recover i would say most
people can do three to four sets you
know three times a week so say you did
four sets three times a week that's 12
hard sets of hip thrust per week and
that's assuming you have productive
sessions yeah everyone could do 100 sets
a week but you wouldn't be recovered
you'd be very weak you'd be sore as hell
you'd be weak you'd have to go way down
and load and use really light weights so
i'm talking productive sessions here
right so with pure heavy barbell
training maybe you can get around
12 sets a week and still be recovered
you can fine tune that you can have a
lot of barbell resistance and then only
a little bit of band resistance or you
can have very little bar resistance
meaning not a lot of plates added and
then tons of band tension at the top so
for example say you have a 400 pound
bench you could have it to where it's
350 here and 400 here or you could have
it to where it's you know 135 here and
400 here if i had to guess the sweet
spot i would say it's different for
every lift with bench press i would
think you'd want around two-thirds of
the weight
down at the bottom and then the lockout
is the maximum weight per the desired
rep range whereas other exercises like
hack squats i think pure band tension is
ideal why do i think this because i've
been doing tons of banded hack squats
lately here's the deal i freaking love
hack squats they annihilate my quads the
problem is
they're too good at hitting my quads you
know i don't have the biggest legs but i
can do 10 plates you know 450 pounds for
eight reps in the hack squat it makes my
quads so sore and it's also hard on my
knees you know my patellas are sore for
four days afterwards so i can't train
quads until five days later but if i set
up with bands i have a heavy band and an
average band on there you know it's not
a lot of load at the bottom but it is so
hard to lock out watch me doing these
i'm like at the top i'm trembling it
even pulls me down so hard into the
bottom because it's hard to resist
slowly on the way down but i can do that
for eight reps the next day i'm not sore
so if i do regular hack squats i can
only do them once a week but if i do
banded hacks once i could do them three
times a week just fine and when i do
regular hack squats i only do two sets
because if i go to true failure they
annihilate me so i can really do like
two sets a week of going all out crazy
to failure hack squats but i should also
mention that i'm pretty good at pushing
myself you know people who train with me
tell me man i've never seen anyone push
themselves so hard on a set so i can
only do a couple sets a week of
traditional hack squats but i could
probably do 9 to 12 hard sets of banded
hack squats per week and recover just
fine i've been doing banded hack squats
at glute lab when i go to san diego and
i've been doing band seated hack slides
here in my vegas gym when i'm home my
and my quads and thighs are the biggest
they've ever been right now and i know
that it's from all the extra volume that
i'm able to handle with all the band
training and once again this is
especially important for people who
experience a lot of muscle damage who
tend to get very sore or people who tend
to get injured easy you know i have some
friends who they're always getting hurt
they're very injury prone their their
muscle strength outstrips their
connective tissue strength you know you
know if their soft tissue could handle
it they could be world-class elite
lifters but they're always getting hurt
they're tearing a muscle they're tearing
their meniscus and their knee they're
they're getting fai in the hips they're
getting disc herniations those people
should definitely consider bar plus band
training you know in the research
there's a huge genetic element to muscle
damage some people can do the same
workout you know and one person gets a
lot of muscle damage from it gets
annihilated and the other person does it
and there's genes that are responsible
for this so my hypothesis could be true
for everyone but it is more likely to be
true for the people who experience a lot
of muscle damage and our injury prone
now back to the topic of research in
order to provide really sound evidence
as to which is superior you need a
really unique type of study that's
probably impossible to carry out now i
haven't touched upon the research yet
there are two reasons why i really
decided to take band training seriously
the first reason is westside barbell
club you know louis simmons is a huge
fan of band resistance he's one of the
most respected strength coaches of all
time he's definitely one of the most
influential he's probably the most
influential person in my own training
probably the number one unique
characteristic of his training style was
using bands especially with box squats
they do banded box squats all the time
but they'd also use bands with bench
press with deadlifts and with plenty of
other lifts as well and the second
reason was i kept coming across studies
where it was bar versus bar plus band or
bar versus bar plus chain and when he
used variable resistance when variable
resistance was used
variable outperformed barbell now i
always chalk that up to the novelty
factor i'm like well that's because the
subjects were used to barbell training
then using bar plus band or bar plus
chain is just new it's it's a novel
stimulus then there were just too many
studies that racked up and you know
eventually i paid attention but now i'm
going to tell you why
that research isn't really telling
because when you publish research you're
not going to get it past the peer
reviewers unless you equate the volume
the peer reviewers would want to see
that one group used barbell resistance
you know bars and plates and they did
say you know nine sets a week for bench
and nine sits a week for squats and then
the bar plus band group also did nine
sets a week for squats and bench press
volume was equated if volume was not
equated then you wouldn't know whether
it was the extra volume or the variable
resistance condition you know think of
the scientific method you have to
control all the variables and just
change one thing so if you want to know
what's superior bar or bar plus band
then the logical study design would be
equate volume but one does straight bar
when does bar plus band now let me tell
you why that's not optimal again i've
already touched upon this you can handle
more volume when you add bands in
because it's not as hard in the stretch
so if you really wanted to design a
study to kind of answer that question
which is better bar versus bar plus band
you would need like 200 subjects and
that doesn't happen in strength and
conditioning research especially because
you probably have a 50 drop out if it
was carried out long enough to see a
difference you know say it was a four
month study you know like 16 weeks you'd
probably have 100 people drop out
so you need 300 subjects knowing that
you're going to end up with 200 knowing
that you're going to end up with around
20 subjects per group and you'd need 10
different groups what you'd want is say
one group does three sets
one day a week of say squats bench and
hip thrusts okay and you're gonna look
at strength outcomes and hypertrophy
outcomes you know you're gonna look at
quads glutes and pecs all right the next
group does three sets two times per week
with just straight weight you know
barbell the next group does three sets
three times a week then four times a
week and then another group five times a
week so five different groups with the
straight weight so that ranges from
three sets a week to 15 sets a week per
exercise then you'd also do the same
with the bar plus band group you'd have
one group doing three sets of bench hip
thrusts and squats with bar plus band
resistance and you'd have them doing
that one two three four or five days per
week now if i had to guess what i would
predict is that going five days per week
with just straight barbell weight for 16
straight weeks that would lead to over
training that would be detrimental
they'd see diminished gains because it
was too much for them to recover from my
guess
is that the two or three or maybe the
four but probably the three day week
frequency would be optimal for the
barbell condition but in the bar plus
band group you probably see that the
four or the five day group was optimal
and then you could compare the optimal
condition for barbell versus the optimal
condition for bar plus band and see
which led to greater growth and my guess
would be that the bar plus band would
see greater growth
due to the lesser muscle damage and the
greater volume that they encountered
throughout the 16 weeks you know they
would have had a much larger volume load
too much muscle damage is problematic
it's detrimental to performance it
interferes with your training frequency
one final benefit i'd like to add about
band training is when you have a little
bit lighter load at the bottom you tend
to have better posture better mechanics
out of the hole it's kind of like bar
plus band training is technique training
because you know it's not going to be
hard so when you're doing bench you
lower it into the right position you
know when you're doing squats or
especially like deadlifts you'll set up
with a better arch you're not gonna
round or shoot the hips up because it's
easy out of the bottom it's hard at the
top so it actually leads to better
mechanics so now i've gone on and on
about band training why it's awesome and
explain the logical rationale of why you
should be incorporating it now let me
show you how we use band training in
glute lab here we see banded squats now
we never use just pure band resistance
for squats we always use it with
resistance but we do banded squats with
the barbell we do free squats we do box
squats we also use bands with the smith
machine and let me show you how i use it
on the smith machine as you'll see here
first i don't line my feet up way out in
front i use a vertical smith machine for
these and i line my toes up with the
vertical upright this puts me in the
same exact position at the bottom of the
movement as regular squats do now see
how i connect the bands and i can adjust
this by moving the bands up a notch or
two now this is my smith machine in
vegas but you got to get crafty you know
you got to figure out ways to use the
bands and i figured out how to use them
with my equipment all right so you can
modulate the tension if you want less
you put it here
more here
you can even go way up you know
to there
that would be really really hard
but using this system we also do this on
the power rack
you can see how you know beginners
would be here
and then this would be way less tension
uh way less slack on the bar so
that's how we use the smith machine we
also do that in the rack now with
deadlifts we use bands two different
ways the first is just you know with the
barbell it's bar plus band we have a
special power rack at glute lab you know
i had elite fts design it for me it
makes it very easy to perform band
resisted deadlifts the other way is we
do reverse band deadlifts okay it just
has a little bit different feel with the
banded deadlifts it feels more natural
at the bottom but the lockout feels a
little bit artificial whereas with the
reverse band the bottom feels a little
unnatural but the lockout feels more
natural they provide similar amounts of
additional tension at the top bench
press here's how we do banded bench
press and this is our bc strength power
racks which are going to be coming out
soon but as you can see it's just one
hole in it makes it so convenient for
bench pressing with hip thrusts we use
bands two different ways okay
we do bar plus banded hip thrusts all
right and that's why i designed the hip
thruster you know i designed my first
hip thrust device in 2006. the scorcher
and the scorcher had crazy amounts of
band resistance then i designed the hip
thruster 1.0 and then finally the 2.0
and it's very conducive to band training
with hip thrust band training just feels
great you know making that lockout extra
hard it's awesome if you don't have a
hip thruster you can still do band hip
thrust in a power rack or by using
dumbbells it's just a pain in the butt
you know having that hip duster is
really nice we also use pure band
resistance you know just bands that pure
band it's like nothing at the bottom
everything at the top so for that reason
we do pulses we don't go down all the
way now we also use bands on all the hip
thrust machines we use uh bands with the
smith machine hip thrust with the
nautilus glute drive and with the booty
builder you know nautilus and booty
builder were smart enough to say we're
going to add an option for bands with
the machine which is rare kudos to them
for doing that because how many
commercial gym machines have
options for adding bands to it not many
and here's how we use it with those
machines okay all right we also do
banded chin ups now i'm not talking
about band assisted chin ups okay
obviously beginners do band assisted
chin up so we actually do band resisted
chin-ups and we started doing this with
our strong lifting training you know we
found that you can do band resisted
lifts more frequently so we'd have one
day a week where you do regular chin ups
or weighted chin-ups and then another
day a week where you do band resisted
and you can recover more easily from
that second session so what we do here
is we put a long band you know the 42
inch bands so you put one end around
your neck and the other end attached to
a dumbbell dropped beneath you we have a
tall rack so it makes it really hard to
get the lockout we also start using
bands with military press and we add
resistance the same way we do with the
smith machine squats you know you could
really do this for all the lifts if you
did them inside a power rack but see how
we use the extra t-handle to modulate
the resistance you can fine-tune however
much you want that to stretch you know
for beginners they can't handle as much
tension at the top whereas for more
advanced they might be able to go up
even higher or even maybe even double
loop it in some exercises but this is an
awesome way to carry out band resistance
because sometimes a single loop isn't
enough tension but a double loop is too
much tension so this lets you meet in
the middle and give it just as much
tension as you want at the lockout we
also do
standing shoulder press with the bands
with handles where you stand on them and
that's you know real easy at the bottom
really hard at the top but those require
the special bands that have the handles
on them we use bands with 45 degree
hypers now you could
kind of use light resistance and also
hold on to a dumbbell but when we do
these we usually just put the band
around we don't combine it with the
dumbbell so
i put the band around my neck people
think oh is that dangerous for your neck
no not at all it looks dangerous but
it's not the girls tend to put it around
their upper back so they wrap their arms
through and wrap it around and they have
the bands around their upper back but
the guys tend to put it around their
neck because it's harder that way when
you have around your neck you stretch it
just a little extra further than you do
when you have it around your upper back
and the new bc strength 45 degree hyper
has those band pegs so that makes it
super convenient to do banded 45 degree
hypers now as i already mentioned in
this video we do banded hack squats and
seated hack slides with the hack squats
we typically do pure band because it's
so hard but you can also add plates if
you want you can fine tune it and with
the seated hack slides we typically
combine it you know
but it's way more band tension than
plate tension so it really works the
lockout it's super easy at the bottom
super hard at the top these are growing
my quads my quads have never been bigger
now we do banded lying leg curls and
this is just pure band tension these are
really nice these are underrated i've
been doing these since before i even
owned my first gym when i trained out of
my garage
probably i think 2003 is when i started
doing these i've been doing these for 18
years awesome exercise we do seated rows
with pure band tension and this is
another one i came up with i've never
seen anyone else do it but i started
doing these also in around 2003 out of
my garage that's just because i didn't
have a cable column yet and i wanted to
do cedar rows so i bought the seated row
handle and i would attach a heavy band
and then just row it in but this really
works that squeeze you really feel the
scapula the retractors on this one we do
supine pull downs either with one arm or
two arms and this we start doing during
the quarantine because you know you're
training from home if you don't have a
chin up bar at home how do you work that
pull down motion well here's how you do
it what i like about this is it works
that lockout which is where most people
struggle during chin-ups it's that last
little bit now here's an exercise i made
up the face pull pull apart okay people
did band pull aparts right and then
people also were doing banned face pulls
what i started doing is i'd grab just
the right amount to where it was hard to
pull apart
but it'd be really far away from the
support and i'd do a face pull pull
apart so i would row like this as i
pulled the bands apart you got to grip
it just the right amount now face pulls
mainly work the upper back like the
scapular retractors like the mid traps
and the rhomboids but when you add the
pull apart motion it works the rear
delts thoroughly i was very surprised
when i conducted emg
experiments and i found that these were
the rear delts as good as most of the
rear delt exercises i started paying
attention wow you really do feel that in
the rear delts all right we do feet
elevated glute bridges you can do this
on the hip thruster we've also done it
on the bench press in glute lab but
these kind of take the quads out of this
is mostly hammy and glute these are
these are gnarly people love these i
don't know why i don't do them more
often they're very well received three
more quad machines that we use bands
with are the lever squat the leg press
and then the belt squat it's nice that
we have the pit shark so they have an
option for band usage with the pitch
shark machine and you can use the bands
with the belt squat or even if you do
straddle lifts with the seat row handle
which is more like a deadlift now we
don't do the following exercise that
much but i have used it with incline
press before here's how we do it you can
do band resisted dips it's not easy but
here's how it's done banded tricep
extensions i used to do these all the
time before i had a cable column these
used to be a staple when i just had a
garage gym with no cable column but now
i don't do them as much banded curls in
theory i think i'd really like these but
i just don't do them that much and then
finally the band standing lateral raises
and finally the different delt raises
you know i typically do this with the
bands with handles you can do upright
rows front raises lateral raises and
then you can drag the bands up a support
beam
crisscross them and do rear delts so
those are all the ways we use bands at
glute lab but i should also mention that
we use the glute loop all the time and
the glute loop is a band it's a cloth
band but it provides elastic resistance
it's just it's shorter it's smaller what
i love about the glute loop is the same
thing you can use this every day and you
can recover from it and i like it when
men act like you know the like these
these booty bands are wimpy these glute
loops are for just for girls they're not
for guys i use it three times a week i
do all the exercise that i tell my girls
to do and i freaking love it and these
get my glutes burning so good some
nights while i'm watching netflix i'll
do knee banded hip thrusts you know i'll
just sit put my back on a couch and do
you know four sets of 25 hip thrusts
while i'm pushing out all right other
times i'll
you know put the bands above my knees
and i'll do seated hip abductions where
i lean back and crank out 30 reps
straight up crank out 30 then lean
forward and crank out 30 reps i'm always
doing lateral band walks you know i do
them in place left right left right and
i try to stay upright when i do those
and those hit my upper glutes really
well but my favorite thing is just to do
band standing hip abduction and i go
straight out to the side you know i'll
do two to three sets of 20 with these
they annihilate my upper glute you know
my glute medius and upper subdivision
the glute max then i follow it up with
two to three sets of 20 to 30 rep
kickbacks and those hit the entire glute
max and you can do those straight back
or kind of diagonal both ways work well
you know there's a lot of other
exercises you can do with the bands but
those are the ones that i use most and
that i prescribe most with my clients so
there you have it these are the most
common ways that i use bands in my
training at glute lab with my clients
and with myself so i've laid out a
theory i've provided a good argument as
to why bar plus band resistance could be
superior to straight barbell training i
don't think it'll become mainstream for
the reasons i mentioned earlier that
bands can break they're dangerous
they're annoying to carry around they're
annoying to set up and they're a
liability for gym owners because they
could break and hurt someone and they
get stolen they have a way of
disappearing and you have to replace
them all the time when you have them in
commercial gyms because they get used so
much and in my experience commercial
gymers don't like to be ordering things
you know every month or two they want to
buy something once and not even think
about it for you know years to come what
i do hope and expect is for this video i
hope it's well received i hope this
opens up a lot of people's eyes to the
merits of bar plus band resistance and
they start incorporating it more into
their own training and if you have a
garage or a home gym it's a no-brainer
so give it a try see if you can handle
more volumes see if it allows you to
train more frequently and see if it adds
to your strength and muscle growth if
you're like me you will be pleasantly
surprised alright that's a wrap thank
you very much for watching the video if
you like what you see please remember to
hit like definitely leave a comment if
you have any questions about band
training and always
make sure you're subscribed to my
channel i have a lot of good things to
come in 2022. thanks again for watching
if you like what you saw in this video
and you want to train under my system
and principles then i invite you to
click on the link below and subscribe to
booty by brett and join the thousands of
other happy members who are seeing
amazing results
yes
[Music]